I feel like something that really encompasses this Python philosophy is how easy it is to convert between data types.
And this is something I tend to use all the time.
So first we'll talk about some string operations.
But let's say we have a string and it is a comma separated string.
What data type does this look like?
But what kind of data do we see out in the real world that looks like this?
Yeah, a CSV file.
Has everyone worked with CSV files?
There are a text representation of data.
So usually they'll have a comma separated column line and then all of your data is there in the file.
Separated just in text with commas.
So if you have you know other programming languages, how might you approach taking this CSV file and then breaking it up into something that's actually useful?
Yeah.
So in Python we can split this data on the comma and we'll get back a list.
And we'll get back a list.
Let's say if we had a student comma separated student.
Mary, she's eight in her favorite subject is a history.
Actually it's math. Mary likes math.
Now we can say student dot split on the comma and we'll get back a list.
We saw a little bit of tuple unpacking yesterday.
I mentioned that you can also unpack variables from a list.
It was just not as common, but I can go ahead and do that.
So I can just say name, age and subject is equal to student dot split.
Right? Because student dot split gave me the list.
And now I have Mary's name. I have her age. I have her subject.
Super easy to throw this in a loop, right?
If you have to go through multiple lines.
If I had, I have my data. I'm going to make a list out of it.
But I'm going to split on that comma again.
So now I have my list of individual items that were split by the comma.
If I wanted to combine all the items in this list back together,
the easiest and best or most efficient way to do this is with a join.
So this syntax for join is a little bit weird.
I see this trip up winners, but you'll want to start with your
Dillimeter here. And then call join on that.
And you'll pass in a sequence to join.
So here I'll use my list.
And now we'll see our new Dillimeter here.
If you want to make this easier to read, for example, to make it back into the CSV,
I can also add a space here.
And that will easily just put a comma after each word.
Notice that Python is smart and doesn't include the trailing one.
In other languages, this is a lot harder, a lot more complicated.
We know that we saw yesterday that we can pass strings into the integer.
The integer type and get back an int back.
We can, you know, make float numbers.
As you learn about looping and company hunches and working with your data,
you'll see exactly how powerful this is.
So open up your course website.
If you haven't already, click on date to intermediate Python.
If you don't see it there, you might have to refresh your site.
And then we're in chapter one exercise.